# The Head of The Human Resource Department

# Asia Cyber University (UNSIA)

Jl. Harsono RM, Ragunan, Pasar Minggu, Jakarta Selatan DKI. Indonesia.

Telp.: (021) 27806189

Email: unsia.sdm@gmail.com

Dear Mr. / Mrs,

I am really interested and motivated to apply for the position as **Lecturer in Information Technology at Asia Cyber University.** 

I am 45 years old. I was PhD (Computer Science) from the Faculty of Information Science and Technology (FTSM), National University of Malaysia (UKM) in 2017.

My research focuses on Education Technology, Artificial Intelligence, Data Visualization, Image Processing, Pattern Recognition, Machine Learning, GIS, programming Language. I am especially interested in Document analysis in image processing.

Enclosed please find a copy of my curriculum vitae. I have sent recent color photographs, detailed work experience and my contact information has listed on my CV.

Thank you very much for your consideration and I look forward to hearing from you as soon as possible.

Best regards,

Dr. Sitti Rachmawati Yahya, S.T., M.TI.

+60166876153 / +60195488154

# CURRICULAR VITAE (CV)

I on behalf named below declare some intimation themselves to a notice to Mr. / Mrs., is as follows:



#### **GRAINS OF PERSONAL**

Full Name : **SITTI RACHMAWATI YAHYA**Place and date of birth : May 14, 1975, Jakarta, Indonesia.

Passport Number : B9567796. Citizenship : Indonesian.

Address : No. 11, Jalan Setia 2, Taman Intan Setia,

Tanjung Malim, 35900, Perak, Malaysia.

Phone Number : Hp. +60166876153 / +60195488154 / +60163656350

E- Mail : sitti.rachma@gmail.com

Gender : Female. Marital Status : Spouse.

Husband Name : Dr. Makmur, MA.

Childrens Name : 1. Nur Izzatul Fariha.

2. Muhammad Wafiiq Khairullah.

3. Nur Qanita Afifah.4. Nur Fina Azizah.

Parents Name : 1. Haji Muhammad Yahya Sibe, SH, MH.

2. Hajjah Sitti Rosmawati Umar.

Parents Husband : 1. Haji Harun Kannebu.

2. Hajjah Sitti Marwiyah Abdullah.

Health : Very good but never had surgery when giving birth.

Hobby : Multimedia and computer learning, internet surfing,

fashion, tour, and contemplative nature.

## **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

2008 - 2017 : Ph.D for Computer Science, Faculty of Technology and

Computer Science, National University of Malaysia

(UKM) Bangi, Selangor Darul Ehsan, Malaysia.

2003 - 2006 : Master of Science and Information System, Faculty of

Technology and Computer Science, National University of

Malaysia (UKM) Bangi, Selangor Darul Ehsan, Malaysia.

1993-1997 : Bachelor of Information and Technology, University of

Gunadarma, Depok, West Java.

1990-1993 : SMAN 1 Depok, Depok 1, West Java.

1987-1990 : SMPN 2 Depok, Depok 1, West Java.

1981-1987 : SDN 2 Depok, Depok 1, West Java.

1983-1987 : Madrasah Diniyah Al-Muhajirin Depok, Depok 1,

West Java.

1980-1981 : TK Tunas Harapan Nusa, Depok 1, West Java.

## **ACADEMIC ELIGIBILITY**

July 2017 : PhD for Computer Science, Faculty of Technology and

Computer Science, National University of Malaysia

(UKM).

(CGPA: 3.05).

Mac 2007 : Master of Science and Information System (UKM)

(CGPA: 3.05).

February 1998 : Bachelor of Information and Technology (Gunadarma)

May 1993 : Certificate of SMAN

Jun 1990 : Certificate of SMPN

Jun 1987 : Certificate of SDN

#### **ACADEMIC SUBJECTS**

- **Ph.D for Computer Science**, Faculty of Technology and Computer Science, National University of Malaysia (UKM): *Kaedah Penyelidikan dalam teknologi Maklumat 2*.
- Thesis of Ph.D: Image Restoration And Reconstruction Of Old Document Using Compound Binarization And Recursive Connected Component Labelling.
- Master of Science and Information System, Faculty of Technology and Computer Science, National University of Malaysia (UKM): Kaedah Penyelidikan dalam teknologi Maklumat, Sistem Maklumat Eksekutif, Pengkomputeran Klien-Pelayan, Pengurusan Projek, Bahasa Melayu 1 & 2, Pemprosesan Bahasa Tabii, Sistem Maklumat Perakaunan dan Kewangan.
- Thesis of Master: Pengecaman Telapak Tangan Berasaskan Ciri-Ciri Wavelet.
- Academic Subjects in Bachelor of Information Technology: Faculty of Information Technology, Gunadarma University, Jakarta, Indonesia: Algoritma and Programming 1 & 2, Introduction of Computer System, Introduction of Information System, Aljabar Linier, Matematic Distkrit, Graf & Algoritma, Introduction of Neural Network Connection, Teory of Computation, Algoritma Pengolahan Paralel, File and Accses, Struktur Data, Perangkat Lunak Aplikasi, Programming Structure, Introduction of Basic Data, Tecnical of Operational Research, Communication Data, Basic Data, Pengolahan Data Distribution, Computer Arcitekture, Sistem Penunjang Keputusan, Rangkaian Digital, Logika & Aljabar, Kalkulus 1 & 2, Statistika & Probabilitas, Struktur Bahasa Pemrograman, Basic Numeric Methode, Analisis & Perancangan Sistem Informasi, Bahasa Rakitan, Computer Grafic, Analisis Numerik & Fortran, Pengolahan Citra, Automata & Bahasa Formal, Operational system, Mikroprosessor, Rekayasa Perangkat Lunak, Methodology Research, Simulasi, Technical Compilation and Others.
- **Thesis of Bachelor:** Penggunaan Rs-232c Pada Sistem Barcode Gunadarma.

#### **CO-CURRICULUM ACTIVITY**

- 2020. Webinar Series, Image Processing and Its Real Application, APTIKOM, Jakarta, Indonesia.
- 2020. Webinar Series, Machine Learning for Decision Making, APTIKOM, Jakarta, Indonesia.
- 2020. Webinar Series, Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning, Model and Implementation, APTIKOM, Jakarta, Indonesia.
- 2020. Webinar Series, Deep Learning: Concept. Model, Algorithm, and Applications, APTIKOM, Jakarta, Indonesia.
- 2020. Webinar Series, Professional Talk: Academic Entrepreneurs, IEEE Instrumentation and Measurement Society (IMS) Malaysia Chapter.

- 2020. Public Lecture, Webinar Series, Satelite Image Processing, Universitas Nasional, Jakarta.
- 2020. Public Lecture, Webinar Series, Pengenalan Machine Learning Dengan Python, Universitas Nasional, Jakarta.
- 2020. Public Lecture, Webinar Series, Trend Technology aringan Di Masa Depan, Universitas Nasional, Jakarta.
- 2020. IoT Workshop for Beginner, Bluenet Sdn. Bhd., Tech4SchoolAsia, Shah Alam, Malaysia.
- 2019. Creative Multimedia Workshop, UPSI, Perak, Malaysia.
- 2019. Drone Emprit Academic Course & Workshop, Universiti Islam Indonesia, Yogyakarta, Indonesia.
- 2019. Computer User Security Awareness Course, Iverson Sdn. Bhd, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.
- 2018, MCAIT Conference of FTSM-UKM, Kuching, Serawak, Malaysia.
- 2016, MCAIT Conference of FTSM-UKM, Melaka, Malaysia.
- 2015, Postgraduate Conference of FTSM, UKM, Bangi, Selangor, Malaysia.
- 2011, Australasian Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AI2011), Perth, Western Australia.
- 2010, Matlab Course, Faculty of Technical and Architecture (FTAB) UKM, 2008, Bangi, Malaysia.
- 2010, CMS Joomla 1.0 dan 1.5 Course, FTSM, UKM, Bangi, Selangor, Malaysia.
- 2010, Fuzzy Set, FTSM UKM, UKM, Bangi, Malaysia.
- 2009, International Conference on Electrical Engineering and Informatics (ICEEI 2009), FTSM UKM ITB, UKM, Bangi, Malaysia.
- 2008, Digital Signal Processing Workshop (DSP), Faculty of Technical and Architecture (FTAB) UKM, Bangi, Malaysia.
- 2008, Microsoft Visual C# Workshop, FTSM UKM, Bangi, Selangor, Malaysia.
- 2007, Blue J Java Programming Workshop, FTSM UKM, Bangi, Malaysia.
- 2006, Conference of Seni Budaya and Warisan (Part ICT), Pusat Dagangan Dunia Putra (PWTC), Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia.
- 2005, Postgraduate Seminar of FTSM, Petronas Training Center (PERMATA), Bangi, Selangor, Malaysia.
- 2003, Postgraduate Seminar of FTSM, ESSET, Bangi, Selangor, Malaysia.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

- 1. Makmur Haji Harun, **Sitti Rachmawati Yahya**. 2018. Analisis Dua Tokoh Bahasa Nusantara: Kajian Biografi Raja Ali Haji dalam Manuskrip Bustanul Katibin dan Za'ba melalui Pelita Bahasa Melayu. Jurnal Manuskrip Melayu DBP, Kuala Lumpur.
- 2. Makmur Haji Harun, **Sitti Rachmawati Yahya**, Mohd Kasturi Nor bin Abd Aziz. 2017. Keindahan Seni Lukisan Khat Jawi Kontemporer Nusantara: Analisis Karya Seniman Lukisan Khat Jawi di Alam Melayu. Proseding ke-5 Memartabatkan Bahasa Melayu. Uzbekistan.
- 3. Makmur Haji Harun, Mohd Kasturi Nor bin Abd Aziz, **Sitti Rachmawati Yahya.** 2017. Historiografi Manuskrip Jawi Nusantara: Analisis Sejarah dalam Tuhfat al-Nafis dan Sulalat al-Salatin. Jurnal Serumpun Penulis Budiman. Persatuan Penulis Budiman Malaysia.

- 4. **Sitti Rachmawati Yahya**, Khairuddin Omar, Siti Norul Huda Sheikh Abdullah and Choong-Yeun Liong. 2017. Binarization via the Dynamic Histogram and Window Tracking for Degraded Textual Images. Pertanika Journal of Science & Technology (JST).
- 5. **Sitti Rachmawati Yahya,** Siti Norul Huda Sheikh Abdullah, Khairuddin Omar, and Choong-Yeun Liong, "Adaptive binarization method for enhancing ancient malay manuscript images", In: 24<sup>th</sup> Australasian Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AI2011), Perth, Western Australia, LNAI 7106, pp. 619-627 (2011)
- 6. **Sitti Rachmawati**, S.N.H. Sheikh Abdullah, K. Omar, M.S. Zakaria, and C.Y. Liong, "Review on Image Enhancement Methods of Old Manuscript with the Damaged Background", on ICEEI2009 Conference, FTSM UKM, Bangi, Malaysia.
- 7. **Sitti Rachmawati**, S.N.H. Sheikh Abdullah, K. Omar, M.S. Zakaria, and C.Y. Liong, "Review on Image Enhancement Methods of Old Manuscript with the Damaged Background", on International Journal on Electrical Engineering and Informatics (IJEEI), Vol 2 2009, ITB, Bandung, Indonesia.
- 8. **Sitti Rachmawati**, Khairuddin Omar, Azizi Abdullah, "Pengecaman Telapak Tangan Berasaskan Ciri-ciri Wavelet", on Malay Journal, 2007, FST, UKM, Bangi, Malaysia.
- 9. **Sitti Rachmawati**, Khairuddin Omar, Azizi Abdullah, "Pengecaman Telapak Tangan Berasaskan Ciri-ciri Wavelet", Poster on Seminar Siswazah FTSM, 2005, Pusat Latihan Petronas (PERMATA), Bangi, Selangor, Malaysia.
- 10. **Sitti Rachmawati**, Khairuddin Omar, Azizi Abdullah, "Pengecaman Telapak Tangan Berasaskan Ciri-ciri Wavelet", Poster on Seminar Siswazah FTSM, 2003, ESSET, Bangi, Selangor, Malaysia.

## **MASTER OF LANGUAGE**

Language	Reading	Write	Speak
English	Very Good	Very Good	Good
Arabic	Good	Poor	Poor
Indonesia	Very Good	Very Good	Very Good
Bugis	Very Good	Good	Good

#### PERSONAL CHARACTERISTICS

- Forgiving.
- Humble.
- Helpful.
- Hard working
- Can do the work and responsibilities are be alone and group work (teamwork).
- Ability in finding the best ways and alternatives in problem solving matters.

- Trying for learning and adjusting self-motivated in working under pressure work setting.
- More like work and practical.
- A bit of nature for low profile and not too fond of self-effacing.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

February 2019 – present Senior Lecturer of Information Technology in

Universitas Nasional (UNAS), Jakarta.

January 2008 – December Graduate Research Assistant (GRA) of "Jawi 2010

Manuscript "Research Project in FTSM UKM,

Bangi, Malaysia.

January 2008 – December

2010

Tutor in FTSM UKM, Bangi, Malaysia.

May 2007 - September

2007

Research Assistant (RA) Research Project by title "Development of Electronic Marcet-Place for Efficient Building in Wood-Based Products Industry" in FTSM UKM, Bangi – Malaysia.

May 2001 – February 2002 : Lecturer for subject of Logika Algoritma in

> Sekolah Tinggi Manajemen Informatika & Komputer (STMIK) JAYAKARTA, Salemba,

Central of Jakarta, Indonesia.

September 2001 – February

2002

: Lecturer for subject of Analysis Information System, Subject of PDE in AMIK Bina Sarana Informatika, Kramat, Central of Jakarta,

Indonesia.

January 1999 – : Employees Part Giro in Artha Graha Bank,

Kramat, Central of Jakarta, Indonesia.

September 1997 – September

December 1999

1998

: Assistant of Laboratorium Manajemen Dasar Faculty of Economics, Gunadarma University,

Kelapa Dua, South Jakarta, Indonesia.

## REFEREES

## 1. Prof. Dr. Khairuddin Omar

**Professor** 

Faculty of Information Science and Technology,

National University of Malaysia (UKM), 43600, Bangi, Selangor, Malaysia.

## 2. Prof. Madya, Dr. Abu Hassan bin Abdul

Assoc. Prof. Universiti Pendidikan Sultan Idris (UPSI) 35900, Tanjong Malim, Perak Darul Ridzuan, Malaysia.

# Tanjong Malim, Perak, Darul Ridzuan

October 01, 2020

Sincerely,

(Dr. Sitti Rachmawati Yahya, S.T., M.TI.)